# **SAM AUBER**

#### **ABOUT:**

Game developer with a passion for creating immersive and artistic environments paired with unique player experiences. Over five years of team and solo experience in various aspects of game development with a focus in programming and tech art.

#### **SKILLS:**

## **Programming**

- **C#** games ranging from prototypes to fully released
- C++ prototypes using SDL2 and OpenGL
- Python applications and games using Pygame and PyQt5 frameworks
- Javascript game server features and general web dev

#### **Software and Technical**

Unity, Godot, Unreal, Blueprints visual scripting, Photoshop, Illustrator, Blender, Perforce, Git, GitHub, JIRA, Visual Studio

#### **Miscellaneous**

Agile/Scrum, 3D modelling, Web development, Graphic design, Fluent in French

# **EDUCATION:**

# Falmouth University - Cornwall, UK BSc in Computing for Games

#### **First Class Honours**

September 2017 - June 2020 Key subjects included version control, graphics programming, AI, networking and a focus on developing games in teams.

# College Green - Bristol, UK BTEC in Interactive Media

#### **Triple Distinction\* (D\*D\*D\*)**

September 2014 - June 2016

Key subjects included web development, 2D & 3D animation, graphics design, concept art and game development.

### **EXPERIENCE:**

#### **Lead Programmer on Townbox**

VideoDojo Games, Remote freelance — January 2024 - current

- · Ownership and responsibility of core tech and code base architecture
- Project features and milestone planning
- Major refactoring and rewriting of existing core systems
- · Working alongside the creative director to ensure goals are met

#### **Software Engineer on Sonic Forces: Speed Battles**

SEGA HARDlight, England — August 2022 - February 2024

- Collaborated with artists and designers on the development of multiple new characters and powerups for Sonic Forces
- Developed a character editing and implmentation tool for designers and artists to use when creating new characters for Sonic Forces
- Improved and worked on IAP features to generate more revenue
- Fixed and improved key areas within the Sonic Forces codebase

## **Game Developer on Multiple Projects**

Spelkollektivet, Sweden — April 2021 - July 2022

- Led a team to develop a game prototype in 4 months that was demonstrated at a convention in Poland: Poznań Games Arena
- Developed solutions for rendering bottlenecks in Unity to improve frame rate
- Designed unique visual art styles for projects by coordinating closely with artists and developing shaders using HLSL and shader graph
- Created a procedural bipedal animation system in Unity for characters that I designed, modelled, textured and rigged with Blender

#### Gameplay Programmer on Ruff 'N' Tumble: Mayhem

Psycho Hound, Remote freelance — March 2021 - April 2021

- Collaborated with the lead programmer to add core gameplay features such as the pickup system and the use of weapons
- Optimised and improved existing gameplay features and systems
- Worked with colleagues to test and and troubleshoot gameplay features

#### **PROJECTS:**

#### Planetary Pest Control (award winning game)

Unity | Team of 14 | September 2019 - June 2020

Local 2 player twin stick shooter game awarded "Most Polished", "Best Game Voted by Industry Members" and "3rd Year Most Voted" at the Falmouth GA Expo, and draft selected for the 2020 Rookies Awards

- Rapidly prototyped initial gameplay ideas in order to playtest and select the most engaging concept with the team
- Ideated enemy behaviors that best fit gameplay and game flow with the lead designer
- Independently designed and implemented enemy AI systems,including spawning and behavior trees

#### **Zephyr: The Cloud Odyssey**

Unity | Team of 9 | September 2018 - June 2019

First-person 3D platformer speed running game, downloaded over 700 times in the first 2 weeks of release on itch.io

- Directed project planning, development milestones and deadlines
- Implemented core game loop and systems such as the scoreboard, level manager and objective system
- Developed a responsive first-person character controller for a precise user experience for skill-based gameplay